So health insurance plans with
unlimited sum insured.  Yes, there are two such
plans which provide you unlimited sum
insured.  There
is no limit.  Claim as much as you want.  So let's
talk about what these plans are.  We will
compare both the plans.
We will see what are the similarities and differences in both the plans
and finally we will
also talk about the premiums.  [Music]
Quick reminder before we start the video,
if you haven't already, please subscribe to our channel.
So that you get the right
information at the right time.  Let's move on to the
video.  What are these two plans?   The
first is Neeva Reshore 3.0 and the second is ICIC
Health Elevate. Both have the
option of unlimited sum assured, which means you can
take unlimited coverage.  Meaning there
is no limit, claim as much as you want.  Let us understand
in detail.  So first to
compare both the companies, we will compare the ICR of both.
Which is Incident Claim
Ratio.  Meaning, how much money did the insurance
companies get?  How much did he
pay in the claim?  The claim ratio of Neeva Bhupa
is 59.02%,
this is of last year 2324 end. The
claim ratio of ICICI lmb is 78.85%.
Very soon we are going to
make a video on latest claim ratios also.  So stay tuned.
So now let's talk about the USP of which
plan?
What is the unique selling point of Reash 3.0 on NI Miu?   The
first unique selling point is the locked
clock.  Unlimited sum insured is of course available.
That is the
unique selling point of both the policies.  Lock the clock
means that your premium will
not increase until you make a claim.
Your age will be locked at the current
age.  Let's say you're 31.  You
took the policy on 31st.  If you do not make any claim till the age of 55, then
your premium will be for
31 years.  Now the
premium may increase due to inflation but your age will remain locked
if you do not make a claim.  The second
USP is the worldwide cover you can add.
Meaning, if you
want treatment outside India, that is an option.  You
can add as a rider.  The third one is Cashback
Plus.  Meaning if you do not claim then
you get cashback.  First year 10% and
subsequent year 5% will be added to your wallet every year.  The
Neeb Health application will be
added to the wallet of the person who downloads it.
And every three years you will get a booster of
10%.  This amount will be in the wallet which
is equal to Rs.  Meaning, suppose
if you have ₹000 points then there are ₹5,000 which you
can use on OPD, which you
can use on copay, deductible, you can
also use this Cashback Plus
wallet to pay premium.  The next USP
is Well Consult Plus which is an OPD
rider.  OPD has very comprehensive
coverage.  You get OPD cover up to Rs 1 lakh.  If you
want to see its detailed video, it
is available on our channel.  Link is
given in description box.  The next USP
is Day One cover of 145 pieces.  There are 145 pre-
existing diseases which you
can get covered from day one by paying additional premium in NEBUPA
3.0 plan or by taking rider.  Now let us come to
what is the USP of ICICI LBAD Elevate Plan
?  The first USP is the power
booster.  There is a rider add-on in this
which keeps increasing your sum assured by 100% every year.
But this power booster will
not be useful in unlimited sum insured.  If you are
taking a policy with low sum assured like Rs 10 lakh, 20
lakh, 50 lakh, 1 crore then you
can take Power Booster.  With this your sum assured will keep
increasing by 100% every year.  There is no need in Unlimited
because the sum assured itself
is unlimited.  It has inbuilt sibling discount.  If
your CIBIL is good then you can get a discount of up to 20%
on your policy
premium.  Third is jump start.  You can check your
day one pre existing conditions which are
asthma, BP, cholesterol, diabetes.
You can get all this covered from day one by
paying an additional premium that is called Jump
Start.  Now let us move towards the basic benefits and
eligibility criteria.  First room
eligibility.  So, Room Eligibility ReS
3.0 has come in four variants – Classic,
Select, Elite and Black.  General
ward will be available in Classic.  The Select plan offers twin
sharing rooms.  The Elite plan has a single
private AC room.  Except Suite and
Deluxe.  and Any Room in Black Plan.  You
can take any room.  You have room modifier option
in Single Private AC Room at ICIC Low LBA Elevate.
You can choose to downgrade or upgrade the room.
Minimum Maximum Entry Edge The
minimum entry edge in Nema Rear 3.0 is 18
Maximum No limit.  And dependent
children can be added to the policy from 91 days to 30 years.  The
minimum entry age in ICC LB Elevate is 18 and the
maximum is 125.  So essentially there
is no maximum entry age.  Dependent
children can also remain with the child for a period of 91 days to 30 years.
Minimum and maximum sum
assured.  So, Minimum Sum Assured (NSAs)
policies of five and ten lakhs
are also available in NIMA 3.0.  But why is this policy considered
?  For Unlimited Sum Assured.
Similarly, I Anomard Elevate also
starts from Rs 5 lakh.  It goes up to
unlimited sum assured.  But here since
we are comparing unlimited, we will
consider unlimited only.  Policy Tenure.
You can also take policy for 1 year, 2 years, 3 years, 4 years, 5
years.  You
can pay an upfront premium.  2 years, 3 years, 4
years, 5 years old.  You get some multi tenure
discounts.  So you can also take a policy of two, three, four or five.
Available in both companies.  Resource 3.0 as well as ICIC
Low Elevate.  Day Care Day care procedures are
covered up to the sum assured
in both the policies.  There are day care procedures
that do not require 24-hour hospitalization.
You go in the morning and come back
home in the evening.  Because of advancement
of science and technology.  So both the
policies cover up to the sum insured.
Ayush Hospitalization.  Which is
Ayurveda, Yoga, Unani, Siddhanta,
Homeopathy.  Their hospitalization
is covered up to the sum insured.  Then your
domiciliary hospitalization.  Domiciliary means
that the patient is so critical that he
cannot be taken to the hospital or if
beds are not available in the hospital then he is getting
treatment at home.  Which is called
domiciliary hospitalization.  Hospital at home
is also covered in both the policies up to the
sum insured.  Emergency Road Ambulance.  So the
road ambulance to go to the hospital, which is an
emergency road ambulance, is covered as per
actuals in both the policies.  Emergency Air
Ambulance This is also your cover up to Rs 5 lakh in Nivapa 3.0.
And you can add riders through ICIC NOB Elevate.
You can add through additional premium.
You can add-on annual health checkup
by opting for additional riders and on a cashless
basis through the Nima Health app.
You can also
add your annual health checkup through the rider in ICC LB Elevate.
Pre and Post Hospitalization
Expenses: The expenses incurred before and after going to the hospital are
reimbursed.
So in Niva Reshore 3.0,
you can get the expenses reimbursed for 60 days before and 180 days after.
In ICIC LB Elevate,
you can reimburse expenses of 90 days before and 180 days after.  So
what actually comes under these expenses?
Meaning, before the reason for hospitalization, you might have
consulted a doctor,
attended OPDs, taken some medicines, got
tests done, all of these come
under pre-hospitalization.  You can also get that reimbursed
after you get discharged.  And
post hospitalization happens.  Many times the
doctor prescribes you some medicines
that you have to take for six weeks
or four weeks or you
go to the doctor again for follow up for the same
thing for which you were hospitalized.  So
you can get all that reimbursed.  Those who get any test done can
also get it re-examined.   If it
is an accidental case and physiotherapy
is prescribed or any surgery has been done where
physiotherapy is prescribed, then physiotherapy is also
covered in post-hospitalization.
Unlimited e-consultation is available in Neevapa 3.0
and in ICCMA Deliver you
can add on Unlimited e-consultation.
Next comes modern treatments and
robotic surgeries.  Both policies
cover up to the sum insured.  If you are
buying the lower variants of Reashore 3.0,
Classic and Select, then there is a subvention of Rs 1 lakh.
Non Payable Items So
you can add non payable items through rider.
NIVAPA has a Claim Safeguard Plus
rider which covers all four natures.
Annexure 1 2 3 47 is a list of items that
you can add to Claim Non Payable Items.
With Claim Safeguard Plus.
Riders can also be added to ICICI LBA Elevate.
Which is claim protector that
covers your non-payable items.  OPD
cover.  So there is OPD cover rider.  Well Consult
Plus is a rider.  Where you get OPD up to Rs 1 lakh.
Its detailed video
is also available on our channel.  You can check.
And the ICIC LBD Elevate has a B Fit
rider that you can put on.  There
is a separate video for that too.  If you want to take it then you can
definitely see it.  It will be
helpful.  Voluntary Copayment You want
me to make a copayment so that my
premium is reduced.  What
is copayment?  Suppose 100% claim comes.  Out of that
you say that I will pay 20%.  So
what will happen with that?  The company will provide 80%.  If you pay 20%,
you will get a discount on the premium.
If you want to enter the Venturi comment
where the pay age increases and the premium
increases, then you can take it.
Venture copayment is available in both the policies.
You can choose whatever you want.  It
is optional.  Then comes the deductible.   The
deductible is basically a percentage, like a co-payment.
Deductible is an amount.   It has to be
given first before the insurance company
starts the cover.  So lets say you have a
deductible of Rs 30,000 and you have
unlimited sum insured.  If any
claim comes to you then you have to pay ₹00.
Suppose a claim of ₹ lakh comes, then you will pay ₹ 0000 and the
insurance company will pay ₹ 1,70,000.
Similarly, this rider is not available in ICICI LBA right now but the
deductible
is available in NVIVP 3.0.  Maternity Expenses:
Maternity expenses are not available in Niva eShor 3.0
and
you can take maternity and newborn coverage as add-on in ICICI LB
Elevate with two years waiting period.  So
borderless rider is available in global cover Amibap.
Borderless and Borderless for
Specified Illnesses.  Borderless means
any claim coming from outside India
is covered.  Borderless for specified illnesses.
You
can get treatment outside India only for those diseases which are specified.
Next comes world wide coverage
global cover in ICSC Lob Deliver.  So
your worldwide cover is available here also.
Now let us talk about the optional
riders that are available
so that you can make your policy even better.  You
can choose as per your convenience.   Let's
talk about Neema's riders first.
Cashback Plus is what we talked about where you will
get cashback.  If you do not claim it, it will
come into the wallet and you
can use it.  Neema Bupa is one.  This
is an exclusive rider with the Black policy
where you have additional features.  Like
ConCR Services.  Priority Desk
and so on.  Elder One is for Elder members.  There
is an annual health checkup through which
you can get your health checkup done once a year on a
cashless basis.  Heads up.
This is a rider for discount.  If you
say that the doctors of Nivapa will
tell you if you have any disease and which
hospital to go to, then you can take Heads Up for that matter.  It is
explained in detail
in the video of 3.0, you
can refer there.  Then there's the tiered network
discount.  Here you further narrow down your network.  There is a
cashless network.
Inside that you say that we will
go to a tiered network.  So the company gives you 15%
discount.  If you go beyond that there
is a 20% copayment.  There
is also detailed video on tier network.  So
please do refer that.  PD waiting period
modification means you
can reduce the waiting period for pre-existing diseases.  As
we talked about, you can get 145 pre-existing
diseases covered on day one
by paying additional premium.  Then specific
disease weight period modification.
You will see this soon.  You can add this.
Copayment is available, you can choose copayment from 0% to 50%.
Personal
accident insurance that covers your accidental
death and disability.  Hospital
cash benefit means daily cash benefit
for the number of days hospitalized.  If someone is
hospitalized for say 10 days, then at the
rate of ₹4,000 per day,
you get a reimbursement of ₹40,000 for 10 days.
This depends on the sum
assured.  Aggregate deductible as we talked about,
you will choose a deduct amount.   The
insurance company will pay for that.  You will get a
discount on the premium.  Claim
Safeguard Plus for Non Payable Items
is well as Consult Plus OPD Rider.  Borderless stands
for World Wide Cover.  Similarly, ICC
Lomb is the first durable medical equipment in Elvet.
You can choose this.  There
is a dependent accommodation benefit that you
can choose from, and annual health checkups on a cashless
basis.  Claim protector is for non-
payable items.  Power Booster is where you
can increase your sum assured by 100% every year.  Infinite Care where there
is no limit on pay cover.  So
with Unlimited it doesn't make sense.
You can avail domestic air ambulance cover.  The
network advantage that we talked about is
your tiered network.  So tied network
is available here also.  Nursing at home
is available.  Compassionate Visit Inflation
Protector keeps increasing your sum assured every year as per
inflation.
Cornlessness is the benefit.  There
is a critical illness rider.  Where there is a critical illness, the person will be
discharged in lump sum.  Then Personal
Accident which is Accidental Death and
Disability Jump Start to cover PEDs from Day One
Room Modifier where you can
downgrade or upgrade your room.
Copayment is voluntary copayment. Be fit
your OBD riders. Some discounts which are
available in the policy are first discount
on Niva in short three is long tenure
discount. If you take a policy of 2 years, 3 years, 4 years or 5
years then you get long
tenure discount. The company is
paying the premium upfront. Second is
standing instruction discount. If you
put standing instruction on your policy then you get 2.5% discount. There is
live healthy benefit which means you
get up to 30% discount according to the number of steps you walk. Medical
practitioner discount which is 5%.
This is your multitenure discount in ICC Lumbard Deliveroo.  If
you take a policy for one year, two
years, three years, four years, five years,
you are given discounts.
Then your SIBL discount which
we talked about, if the SIBL is good then up
to 20% discount is available.  Now
finally we will talk about the thing which you have been waiting for a long time,
that is premiums.  So let's
talk about premiums,
what is actually the premium of these products.  So I have taken
an age, an example on which
I am calculating the premium.  You
can choose as per your choice what you
want, which rider you want?  Ah, the
premium can be calculated accordingly.
So here I have included the basic rider which is
Safeguard Plus and Claim
Safeguard.  So that non-payable items are also
covered for you.  If you want to take it without it, then
you can calculate without it.
Here we have a family of
three.  31 28 and three are the ages and premiums have been taken for
zone one.  So they are divided into zones.
So here for Pay Zone One with
non payable items coverage.
I told you about two plans, in fact four, Alt and Black.
But we are talking about alt and black.  The
premium price of Alt is 2806 and that of Black
is 2882.  The premium for Unlimited Sum
Insured Claim Protector Rider in ICICI LBA Elevate which
covers your non-payable items
is ₹4148.
So these were the premiums from my side and these were the
details from my side for the unlimited sum
insured plan options.
Many people asked me what
plans are available.  So we thought we would
make a video and give it to you.  If you have
any confusion or
want to reach out for anything, you can reach out to our team.
His contact number is given.
Email ID is given.  You can fill out a Google form.
Our team will connect you.
And before we go, a quick reminder, if
you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, please do so.
So that you get the right
information at the right time.  See you
in the next video.  Till then stay safe.  Take
care.  Bye-bye.